College English Test, Band 6, Part 2, Listening Comprehension.
Section A, Directions.
this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a you must choose the best answer from the four choices marked A, B,
C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1, with a single line through the
centre. Conversation 1.
I'd like to go to the States, but if I took the job there, I wouldn't get a very
good salary. Really?
I thought salaries were high there.
But there would be some fringe benefits, presumably.
Oh yes, it'd stimulating, and it has some advantages.
What else do you have in mind?
Well, there's a position in Portugal.
How does it compare?
It'd offer greater security because it'd be on a home -based contract.
And salary? Much better.
I'd get an overseas allowance, plus free accommodation from the Presumably you'd be
given moving expenses for the Portugal job?
Yes, but just to complicate matters, there's a possibility of a in Sao Paulo.
That's Brazil, isn't it?
Yes, and I'd get a promotion if I took a post there.
I'd love to go to Brazil.
But there are some disadvantages.
I'd have to do a five -year term there.
That's no problem, surely.
Well, not at the moment, but if there were a change in family circumstances, I'd be
a long way from home.
But if you're worried about distance, isn't that the same problem with the States?
Yes, but in the States I'd be on an annual contract, so I could leave fairly quickly
if I needed to.
And Portugal? Well, that's almost next door, isn't it?
I could visit home every few months if necessary.
I can see you've got a difficult choice to make.
Well, fortunately I don't have to make up my mind about any of them yet.
In fact, I haven't even been called for an interview.
What does the name say about the job in the States?
What benefit would the man get if he took the post in Sao Paulo?
What does the man say is the disadvantage of working in Brazil?
What do we learn from the end of
Conversation 2 Good morning.
How are Mountain Savings and
May we help you?
Well, I'm looking for the highest rate possible on a short -term certificate of
deposit account. Well, let's see what we can do for you.
High Mountain is currently offering a rate of 6.4 on a 13 -week account with a
minimum deposit of only $12,000, 6.55
on a minimum deposit of $25,000, and 6.7 on a deposit of $50,000.
Those will have yields of 6.55%, 6.71%, and 6.87%, respectively.
Rate and yield?
I'm afraid I don't understand the difference.
Well, sir, the rate is the percentage of simple interest paid on your money, and the
yield is the total percentage you will receive on your account if you leave your
money with us for at least a at the same interest rate.
Oh, well, I'm not interested in long -term investing, and three months sounds just
fine. Then perhaps you'd like to open one of our high -finance money market checking
accounts. With a minimum balance of only $50,000, you'll get interest of 6.1 on any
amount over that, for a yearly yield of 6.27%.
Of course, there's no penalty for early withdrawal.
Uh, no, thank you.
I... Or, could we persuade you to save with us if we offer you a dining coupon book
that will get you a 25 discount at many of the areas leading restaurants?
At a cost to you of only $12.95.
Look, I think I'll just call around for more information.
Thank you for your time.
Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. What is the man's purpose in making the phone call?
Question 6. What can we know about rate and yield?
Question 7. What is the man most interested in?
Question 8. What did the woman do to persuade the man to deposit in her bank?
Section B. Directions.
this section you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose must the best answer from the four
choices marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Passage 1.
Joaquim de Silva is a Brazilian who lives and works in New York.
Brazil's most important product is coffee, and coffee is Joaquim's business.
He works for an international coffee institute.
It represents Brazil and several other countries that export coffee.
The institute wants more people to drink more coffee.
That hasn't been easy to do for the last few months.
A period of freezing weather destroyed a large part of Brazil's coffee crop.
As a result, there has been a shortage of coffee throughout the world.
The shortage has caused prices to go very high.
Many people are talking about giving up coffee until the prices come down again.
All the countries that are represented in the institute want people to continue
drinking coffee. They spend a lot of time explaining the recent rise in price to
newspaper reporters. They want the public to understand the reason for the shortage.
A month ago, was put in charge of an advertising campaign.
The campaign will try to encourage people to keep on drinking coffee.
Sometimes Joaquim misses the beaches and tropical weather in Rio de Janeiro, but he
likes life in New York.
He's young, only 27 years old, and he's a good -looking bachelor.
There are a lot of women to meet in New York and a lot of to go with them.
When he misses home, there are several Brazilian restaurants where he can go and
speak Portuguese, his native language.
The last few weeks, however, he's been too busy to think about anything except
coffee prices and his advertising campaign.
What does the say about the International Coffee Institute?
What caused the recent shortage of coffee to around the world?
What What do we learn about Joaquim da Silva?
What has occupied Joaquim's for the last few weeks?
What does say about summer, my wife and I had saved for a year to be able to take a
romantic cruise to several Caribbean islands.
Because the train was scheduled to arrive in Miami, Florida several hours before the
sailing, we didn't think we'd have any reason to worry about getting to the on time.
We should have known that long -distance trains are often many hours late.
We should have taken an earlier one to allow extra time.
We should have, but we didn't, and we missed the boat.
Because there wouldn't have been a refund on our cruise fare if we'd returned home,
we had to pay for a hotel room and meals in the city and an airfare to fly to the
first island on the ship's route two days later.
We missed half the cruise.
This year, we decided to let an experienced travel agent do our vacation planning
for us. We had to pay the full price in advance for an escorted tour.
We should be enjoying that relaxing, well -planned trip right now.
How could we have known there would be a strike against our airline?
And why haven't anyone advised us that a travel agency can't refund your money
unless the tour operator can get the passengers' fees back from the reserved hotels,
the tour bus company, and so on?
To avoid trouble like this, we ought to get more travel experience.
But to tell you the truth, we don't want to go anywhere.
We're planning to spend our vacations at home for a long time to come.
Why did the couple fail to get to the cruise in time?
What does the speaker say about their trip this year?
Question 15. What will the speaker do in the future for a vacation?
Section C. Directions.
In this section, you will hear three recordings of lectures or talks, followed by
three or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Recording 1.
Good evening, and gentlemen.
Today we are honored to have Professor Barnett, who is an expert in dolphin study,
and he will introduce to us the unique characteristics and living conditions of
dolphins. Professor Barnett, please.
Thank you for your introduction, Lisa.
Well, one of the most intelligent animals on the planet is the dolphin.
These unique animals have been regarded highly by humans for many centuries.
In ancient Greece, if sailors saw dolphins swim by their ships when they were
starting out on a voyage, they believed they would have good luck.
One unique characteristic that makes them different from other sea animals is the
way that they communicate.
use sound, touch, and taste in order to learn about their world.
However, unlike dogs, dolphins cannot smell.
They use a whistle or sound waves to see and feel their way around their
environment. This makes them different from many other sea animals and also helps
them communicate with people.
Another unique thing about dolphins is that the bones in their fins are similar to
those in human arms and hands.
However, the connective tissue that surrounds the bones forms a flipper instead of a
hand with individual fingers.
Even though dolphins live in the oceans, they do not drink the salt water around
them. Their bodies absorb water from the wide variety of creatures they eat.
Loving a dolphin is an easy thing to do, but unlike a dog or a cat, the dolphin
cannot come home with you from the ocean.
That is why many people like collecting dolphin souvenirs.
One can find many such things in almost every shop around the world.
Even the ancient people painted the images of dolphins on their vases.
However, dolphins are sometimes hunted in places like Japan in an activity known as
dolphin drive hunting.
Besides drive hunting, they also face threats from habitat loss and marine
pollution. Dolphins have been depicted in various cultures worldwide.
Dolphins occasionally feature in literature and film.
Dolphins are sometimes kept in captivity and trained to perform tricks.
But breeding success has been poor, and the animals often die within a few months of
capture. The most common dolphins kept are the killer whales and the bottlenose
dolphins. Questions 16 to 19 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 16. What makes dolphins different from other sea animals?
Question 17. Why do many people enjoy collecting dolphin souvenirs?
Question 18. What did ancient people do with dolphins?
Question 19. What's happening to the dolphins?
Question 20. happening
Recording 2. British scientists are preparing to launch trials of a radical new way
to fight cancer, which kills tumors by infecting them with viruses like the common
cold. If successful, virus therapy could eventually form a third pillar alongside
radiotherapy and chemotherapy in the standard arsenal against cancer, while avoiding
some of the side effects.
Leonard Seymour, a professor of gene therapy at Oxford University, will lead the
trials later this year.
One of the country's leading geneticists, Professor Seymour has been working with
viruses that kill cancer cells directly, while avoiding harm to healthy tissue.
In principle, you've got something which could be many times more effective than
regular chemotherapy, he said.
Preliminary research on mice shows that the viruses work well on tumors resistant to
standard cancer drugs.
It's an interesting possibility that they may have an advantage in killing drug
resistant tumors, which could be quite different to anything we've had before.
Researchers have known for some time that viruses can kill tumor cells, and some
aspects of the work have already been published in scientific journals.
American scientists have previously injected viruses directly into tumors, but this
technique will not work if the cancer is inaccessible or has spread throughout the
body. Professor Seymour's innovative solution is to mask the virus from the body's
immune system, effectively allowing the viruses to do what chemotherapy drugs do,
spread through the blood and reach tumors wherever they are.
The big hurdle has always been to find a way to deliver viruses to tumors via the
bloodstream, without the body's immune system destroying them on the way.
The therapy would be especially useful for secondary cancers, which sometimes spread
around the body after the first tumor appears.
There's an awful statistic of patients in the West with malignant cancers.
Seventy -five percent of them go on to die from secondary cancers, said Professor
Seymour. Several more years of trials will be needed before the therapy can be
considered for use in the NHS.
Though the approach will be examined at first for cancers that do not respond to
conventional treatments,
Professor Seymour hopes that one day it will be applied to all cancers.
Questions 20 to 22 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 21. What's the big challenge facing virus therapy?
Question 22. What does Professor Seymour want to do with virus therapy?
Amazon.com launched its Kindle library lending service in the United States.
Millions of users of the Kindle Reader and app can now borrow Kindle books from
their local public library.
The service will be available through the websites of more There 11,000 local
libraries across the country.
Users of other devices have already been able to borrow library books.
Experts say Amazon's entry is likely to reopen a debate between publishers and
libraries over e lending.
Bill Rosenblatt is president of Giant Steps Media Technology Strategies, a
consulting company. He says,
Publishers and libraries are enemies that occur in nature like snakes and monkeys.
Libraries would like to be able to make books available to everyone, all the time,
with no limitations.
And publishers, of course, would like to sell more books to the public.
Mr. Rosenblatt says the debate in the United States centers on what is known as the
law of first sale.
Once you buy any kind of media product, such as a book or a CD or a DVD or anything
like that, you can do whatever you want with it.
You can read it, you can give it away, you can lend it, you can resell it, you can
burn it, whatever you want.
This law is referred to as first sale.
This law is what permits libraries to lend books over and over again without having
to pay publishers each time.
But Bill Rosenblatt points out that it does not include digital products.
Technology known as digital rights management can make e unreadable once they have
reached a certain time or user limit.
Mr. Rosenblatt says several months ago, of the major publishers, HarperCollins,
which is a division of News Corp., announced that they were only going to allow e to
be lent out 26 times, and then they would have to be purchased by the libraries
again. Apart from HarperCollins, publishers are allowing libraries to purchase e for
lending in perpetuity, meaning as many times as anyone wants to borrow them.
HarperCollins says it took the action to protect the growing e industry and its own
book sales. But Bill Rosenblatt says critics did not see it that way.
They believe a digital book should be lendable forever.
Are based on the recording you have just heard.
What can be learnt about Amazon.com's Kindle library lending service?
What can libraries do according to the first sale law?
Question 25. How did HarperCollins protect the e industry and its own book sales?
This is the end of listening comprehension.